IL Cafe we have you
covered good to have you join us on IL
Cafe welcome to the show my name is
aidel and on today's episode we're going
to be looking at some of those changes
in policy not just within icic lomard
but also in The General insurance
industry that have actually or rather
that are geared towards making the
customer experience uh a lot more
seamless and productive especially when
it comes to that one really important
aspect and that is Claims Settlement now
we do understand that the pandemic has
seen a sort of a Filip in the kind of
initiatives that organizations like ICC
Lombard have undertaken to ensure this
and there have been several things that
have happened to ensure customer safety
is prioritized especially in the
pandemic also seamless you know
integration of the safety with
digitalization sustainability at an
Institutional level all of this has been
implemented at ICC Lombard but then it's
always a good idea to understand
customer Centric and how all of this is
translated into changes uh at the level
of the user right so we've decided to
call on the experts and today we're
going to be catching up with Sanjay data
he is one of the most experienced and
accomplished people professionals that
we have in the insurance industry today
he is Chief underwriting um reinsurance
and claims at IC Lombard he has almost
35 years of experience in this
particular space and he was in fact part
of the launch Team at uh IC Lombard way
back in 2001 so we are in his safe hands
and thank you so much Sanjay for joining
us on iel Cafe welcome to the show hi
you know good to be part of the show and
that was a wonderful you know
introduction to what we do best as a
company which is H the you know customer
at his most distressing point which is
the Moment of Truth for us and for that
customer right it Bas is the promise
which we make when he got you know she
transferred the risk of certain accident
or some even you know unfortunate event
you know affecting their lives or their
properties and so it's you know it's
very very important that we understand
this aspect of the insurance process
which is wholly geared to providing
protection absolutely absolutely and I
have several questions for you Sanjay
but let's start with you know um
customer purchase behavior I'm sure
you've seen it evolve over a period of
time so what are some of the innovations
that the company has brought in in the
claim settlement process uh that speak
to these customer queries that address
the change in behaviors that we've
noticed yes you know the word Innovation
is very important in Insurance there are
you know two three ways where we look at
Innovation one is innovation on products
one is innovation on the you know terms
of the product you know so one could be
completely new category for a different
emerging risk say earlier when you know
when you started a company there was no
such thing as you know big you know
thing in the mind of customers be
corporate customers or for individuals
you know around an emerging risk like
cyber for example you know now it's is
you know slowly Gathering momentum it is
becoming becoming a product by itself
and we looking at those covering those
kind of you know Innovation is happening
in the category of emerging now let's
take uh risks which were always covered
but there's a lot of you know new
coverages being added to certain risk
and we'll talk about that as we go with
same you know very standard motor policy
now seeing a lot of innovation in terms
of what we want to cover and see and
which is very very important is that
there are a lot of in ations in the
claim process which are linked to how
the ecosystem is developing including
the role of technology which serves to
basically do two things one is uh you
know give us a lot of convenience
whether it's on purchase of insurance
but also in lodging and getting a claim
from us but also in the way uh you know
the ecosystem is changing uh in you know
in defining standards of service be you
know the customer you know expectations
you know on how this service will be
delivered and last but not the least in
how we also look at the learnings from
CLS it's not about repeatedly you know
having a claim you know nobody wants to
fall it every day you know people take
lessons from a particular event and then
we kind of shape ourselves to prevent
such occurrences going forward so that
all in all is where Innovation really
plays a part across various parts of the
insurance process right right understood
Sanjay now speaking of customer
centricity and customer friendly
Services you mention mentioned a few of
those over there you also mentioned the
role of technology and uh we're quite
aware that IC Lombard is not new to you
know Digital Services for customers but
that said the pandemic did have the
significant impact on the insurance
industry and digitalization and how the
two of them have sort of found a nice
place to tango so how did IC Lombard
really Embrace digitalization in order
to you know meet these new customer
demands given the pressing needs and
specific nature of the pandemic which
had placed a lot of strain on the the
entire ecosystem I would imagine
pandemic had two kinds of stresses one
is you know it did provide a stress uh
to each one of us individually which we
all are aware of I won't repeat that but
it did you know provide a stress to us
as a company and to the insurance
process and some of that uh you know of
course has benefits on the way the
insurance industry has reacted
especially in India how we as a company
along you know with us the rest of the
industry reacted to let's say pain
claims arising out of the pandemic which
was humongous and and to this day for
the one single infectious disease which
is spread across the population we paid
more than 30,000 CRS now that is of
course it has led to stress for us as a
company and led to stress for the
consumers who've been affected and you
know let to stress for them in trying to
not only fight the disease but also look
at the financial aspects of fighting
this disease so that's one stress which
but what are the other learnings of this
particular event and how did it help us
in terms of drive for digitalization
various other things of course it helped
us a lot you know it actually you know
there are so many things where you know
we do not have a habit we formed a habit
because of so many ideas you know
flowing around habit because we we don't
use those ideas let's say for example
the technology of meeting each other on
the digitally you know these Zoom
meetings teams meetings all of that were
there earlier but the way everyone ad
you know adapted to it and you know took
it on as a measure was was very
important way of you know forcing
digitalization in a big way now beyond
that you know on the personal side as a
company what we how we reacted was we
started looking at you know digitalizing
a lot of our caims process and that came
out of necessity you know and you know
it's the theory of constraint which kind
of drove us you know we could the
customers couldn't meet us we couldn't
meet the customers a lot of them were
not in a position to send us physical
documents then how did we innovate so
obviously we innovated in various ways
you know so we said that you could
download our app so which created an app
which is a service app and it's called I
take care and which through that you
could send a lot of your you know
documents let's say for reimbursement of
covid CLA which you could send it
through that app you know it comes to us
I'm able to process it and send out the
payment electronically back to you there
were a lot of things on the buying
processes a lot of people adapted you
know the whole process of going online
using UPI various modes of premi where
you know these coverages were kind of
renewed with us a lot of people bought
new policies you know especially some of
them bought covid covers which actually
serve to enhance their normal you know
either their own employer employee
coverages or their own personal
coverages because you needed some
insurance for such things that's we
never thought you know it was not you it
was absolutely different from a Deni or
a let's say malaria the cost were
humongous even for treating covid
patient who had a serious covid in so
that was one part the other part which
really came through was the whole issue
of forcing us to relook at our entire
process in terms of digitalization and
what kind of customer convenience we
could we could provide and it did not
end with health only we looked at motor
people you know did not want to come to
our office didn't want we couldn't go to
the you know to let's say to the garages
or the homes to survey their vehicles
could we then you know we had we had
started developing a utility app you
know for selfs survey of video things
that really took up and we did the video
service on line and we were able to
settle claims correct so that that was
the other part which kind of uh helped
their processes a lot similar things you
know on uh the rest of the products in
terms of being they're being able to be
sourced online so so we made a lot of
products available online maybe because
people wanted to transact online and
last but not the least we developed
covers which in terms of innovation
which were in and around the co for
example we realized that not everybody
needs to be hospitalized a lot of people
uh home care really took off so we you
know all our products allowed home care
which was not part of the initial
offering we had so before covid we you
know didn't allow home care but on
because of covid we just let go we
allowed Co everything was digitally
assessed and people you know were able
to digitally send us their you know
claim for basically do doctor
consultation as well as medicines
nothing other than because they stayed
at home and that brought down their
anxiety and especially in the second
wave you know when they didn't need to
go to the hospital a large you know
populations of people were actually
affected they could took treatment at
home they were much more uh in a sense
uh confident of taking treatment at home
and the ones who were really sick
occupied hot hospital bed because
hospital beds came at a premium so you
know that differentiated we put in a
whole process around home you know home
care of you know covid claims and that
really took off that segment so Home
Care became a certain process last but
not is one of the key things like I said
you know a part of the Innovation is
also making sure such things don't occur
we don't end up getting hospitalized we
don't having end up having you know
accident so one of the key things was
how do our products enable people to
look at you know making sure that they
don't end up in hospital so we said
we'll allow we developed a standalone
first time in Industry a product for
outpatient treatment you know cost so we
call it OPD treatment and the product
was big bit and the whole idea was to
make sure that you get get early
treatment for whatever symptom whether
it's co fever or some other thing and
get a diagnosis so in our app which I
talked about I'll take care or even in a
product you were allowed tell Health
consultations and what it meant was that
you could you know sitting at home do
video consultation all that would be
paid for us cashless by our kind of
thing and that completely digitalized
Healthcare uh from a you know uh pair
perspective for we would we would now
paying for you know basically healthare
sitting at your home where you could you
know Tel consult you could you know the
video consult and you know build that
back to us in a cashless manner through
this product right so that that that's
how these things totally change a long
answer to a short question but I thought
it's important to really you know give a
perspective of how Co really kind of set
us to think differently and it was
pushed you know you know kind of a
paradigm shift in the way we operate
absolutely and thank you you know for
sharing all those insights with our
viewers Sanjay it's useful to understand
how customer Behavior at the end of the
day has shaped or rather has uh informed
all these choices and decisions that
have been made in the organization uh
you mentioned motor insurance now sanj I
wanted to understand this a bit better
for the benefit of our viewers because
this is an area where you know claims
are often a source of much uh
frustration so how has the claim
settlement process changed for products
like motor insurance in ic Lombard if
you could do tell a little bit more on
that motor insurance uh has two aspects
you know and unlike other products it
has two very different aspects one is
what happens to the vehicle and you know
when an accident happens you know it
could be you know smallest thing like a
scratch to a big event like a theft or
it could be a total loss when you you
know you are in some Grievous you know
incident where the car is totally
d-shaped right the other aspect of motor
insurance which is extremely important
and which is what the laws of our
country you know especially the motor
vehicles act make sure that you cannot
TR use your vehicle on the road which
has a road you know a permit to travel
on the road without insurance which
basically means that if you hit someone
which you known as third party liability
insurance you need to have third party
liability all the time when you cover if
you don't have it you could be penalized
you could be you know subject to the law
and that is what we provide you know
very clearly now these are two very
separate aspect the third party part let
me come to that earlier is you know
happens to the background so I don't
think the customer gets affect as long
as you know keep us informed we deal
with the third part that's the whole
purpose of a third party liability
people end up going to courts which are
known as motor accident claims tribunal
courts which are specialized Courts for
motor accidents where as insurers I step
into the consumers yous show and deal
with that case and pay for that injury
which which inent just for everyone's
information is Unlimited in this country
there not limited liability it it could
be unlimited for all practical purposes
but we take on that owners because you
are covered automatically as you buy a
new private car or you buy a two wheeler
for you know new private car for three
years two wheeler for five years you're
automatically covered as you buy vle now
you have a choice whether you want to
cover the your vehicle also typically
people when they buy their new car you
know covered their vehicle for the first
year but after one or two years they
tend to not buy insurance for their
vehicle that's why we advise that you do
keep your keep it covered it has two
aspects these are total losses the big
losses which are basically theft and a
big you know damage to your car and
these are there are a lot of partial
damages now the idea is that you
shouldn't have too much of anxiety
either way with a total loss or a
partial loss a partial loss what we have
started using a lot of digital processes
which is basically we are saying that we
will use you know you could let's say
you had to have a windshield damage and
you want it replace you could just call
us we are on a video call you just look
at your video and we have a vendor who
will come to your home and you know fix
that you know sheet correct you have
small as as we call it fender bender
losses very small losses to your door
thing where somebody's grazed your
vehicle and all that you decide whether
you want to claim for that if you want
to claim for that we can you know pick
you know have your vehicle picked up to
the nearest you know garage which is you
know tied up with us could be a garage
you know which is part of the dealer
Network Who Sold you the car could be a
you know stand loone garage it depends
on where you want to take your vehicle
and you could have you know get it
delivered there and people could you
know repair vehicle and give back to you
uh you know in time majority of our
private car planes are cashless which
basically means you don't have to pay
anything you just have to intimate you
know or you go personally go to the
garage or we get get get it picked up it
gets repaired and gets delivered so
that's how has process has become using
the video survey whether with the garage
or all that we are able to deliver our
approvals for these repairs extremely
fast so using digital means whether it's
for that windshield repair for that
bumper repair or for that it's an entire
repair of your four doors because it's
been let's say can of damage in the flat
then you know we just do that onlineer
are able to give the go ahead and you
are able to start repairs the garage is
able to start repairs deliver vehicle as
fast as possible the idea is to bring
down repair time you know and that
depends on us in terms of giving
approval for your repairs based on the
the amount of damage which you know your
vehicle has you know suffered and so
that's another thing last but not least
is the whole process around you know
being able to decide whether you want to
claim or not want to claim and all that
a lot of you know persons are not in
favor of not claiming very small
incidents because it affects the way
their premiums are calculated because
they believe they get a substantial
shaving in the premium because there no
claims uh kind of record you know stays
intact they can get premium discounts up
to 50% because of no clearness and
lastly in motor iting more and more
convenien is coming into the picture
there's a lot lot of innovation which we
have done during the pandemic we've
worked with the regulator on some
sandbox initiative now the regulator has
come out with you know you know uh
certain directives which allows us and
we were the first to launch it in the
thing you know policies where allows you
a floater policy let's be that means you
have two vehicles you are the owner of
two vehicles you can just get it covered
under one policy you have you know a car
and a two wheeler you can get it covered
under Flo of policy convenience of
getting it done at the same time and
also the way the entire claims is handle
for both right and finally you know
nowadays you know the big thing which is
coming is using technology and the whole
convenience part of being able to share
data so we are now getting into a whole
host of measures which looks at two
things how you drive and how much you
drive so we have developed you know pay
as you drive and pay how you drive kind
of uh you know products which you know
then gets into your driving habits and
and also the amount of usage you make up
your car we believe the less you use the
more you know the better you know it is
for avoiding accidents of course and the
you know the more the better you drive
you avoid accidents correct you know a
good driver both of them should be
incentivised on the indan roads because
that's the whole idea is to make sure
that people use car optimally and they
drive it well right and that's where we
are now developing products which
Fosters good behavior on driving on the
roads you know usage wherever it is
required then of course you know you get
better benefits as a car thing and all
that so these are all the host of
benefits we're trying to address motor
becomes a product which is a go-to
product just not a mandatory product
that people buy because that's what the
law of the land said we are trying to
make it into a good customer Centric
product which gives Mobility solutions
for them uh the other area I wanted to
check with you on was uh travel right
because clearly the travel industry as a
whole has been you know has faced a uh
horrendous time um so it would be good
to understand how IC Lombard has
actually worked with the travel industry
perhaps even travel companies and so on
to help improve uh things for example
pretty much the same right the claim
settlement process for products like
travel insurance would be you know good
to understand what we've done here yeah
that's a good one because that you know
traval Insurance in the ecosystem uh to
beating for us as a company as a
industry as a whole because of the fact
that travel virtually stopped for the
first year and a half of the pandemic
nothing happened on travel insurance so
this was the time for us to revamp our
product we said you know travel will hit
back you know add not just only as reng
travel but the fact that world you know
will get back to normal after the
pandemic and people will travel travel
is both Leisure as well as business
travel as well as you know travels for
Education various other things and it
will continue it's something which we
need to you know really look forward to
so here we you know look at two parts
one is what what enhancements and
products can we Pro to take care of you
know exigencies like this so during the
travel first lockdown itself a lot of
people were stranded at various places
you know before they could come back to
India and all of that because they were
traveling there was this sudden lockdown
across these things so in fact lot of
our policies then paid for you know
there you know disruption of store stay
at those for of course once they were
out of India not cancellation of trips
and all that that's you know the travel
insurance has to start you know you know
it started and people were outside we
did pay for all of that went out of the
way to take care of them we going
forward so that's typically going to be
covered in our travel policy going
forward if you face disruption again and
you know how the pandemic is not that
it's going to die at once across the
world there will be Pockets everywhere
each country will have different you
know measures of lockdowns and you know
the way you need to take treatment we
said that you know our tribal policies
should be able to clearly take care of
all of these uncertainties which goes
forward right the the other point is
that a lot of people will we have
started enhancing our product to take
care of various things in into in terms
of leure travel Leia travel is now going
to be become just focused it's not going
to be just group tours to just go and
visit certain places lot of people will
carry out a lot of activities including
at sports somebody would like to you
know try slightly you know extreme
travel you in that sense or longer
duration travels and we our products are
you know meant to gear up to that so
that's second part so we are trying to
make sure product is able to address all
these certainties which are slightly
more high risk than normal travel which
we have and finally you know we're
trying to make sure that uh we have
Solutions in travel for a lot of the
corporates who have lot of the employees
abroad you know in terms of you whether
covering them for their corporate travel
or giving them some sort of solution
where they work and come back you know
to India and all of that right so C of
things we're trying on the Travel front
which is trying to be different from the
prepandemic
right you know I was thinking about it
uh Sanjay as you spoke as you were
telling us about all the you know
different things that we've done the
Innovations uh underway at IC Lombard
and lead I realized that there's one
emotion that underpins a lot of this
right and that's trust um so from a
larger perspective if you to simplify
the insurance business I would imagine
you know catering to that trust element
in customers would be a a critical
aspect so for the benefit of our
listeners of course you know I should
point out that I has an industry leading
ratio in the settlement of claims but
then even so sanj I want to ask you how
has the organization worked towards
building trust with
customers so we we have a very clear you
know about this agenda so we have to
build trust with our good customers
right Insurance process also has
unfortunately based on every society
it'll have even customers or bad right
or ecosystem which are bad we have to
make sure that they don't you know take
undue advantage of the insurance school
which we have created you know the whole
idea is to you know give trust to the
people who buy you know take insurance
it should not be accessed by people who
are wrong correct so that there's a fine
balance between the three but one of the
key features of building trust is
looking at our products to start with
first we're trying to make our products
all inclusive as possible take the
health insurance policy for example
thanks to the regulator who's pushed us
also and we ourselves have you know
worked that part now if you know
everything including is now covered
there was some anxiety where the co
would be covered by health insurance
policy now everything is covered so
which basically means that every you
know every part of the you know uh every
part of any illness which is there
except for illnesses which are not
accidental which is things like cosmetic
surgery or something you know is covered
in your policy we have now started
getting into the Outpatient Treatment
space developing products there so you
there could be confusion what what is
inpatient treatment what is outpatient
we trying to now home care treatment so
it gives a lot of the product is
becoming broad-based so that there's no
confusion around coverage so when you
buy something very clear that you
getting all these coverages which even
for the elements which earlier ised to
fall into secondly we also let's say you
have a different kind of product let's
say benefit product which you know pays
a certain Su when you contracted dis ear
it was very restricted for critical now
we are you know increasing the number of
diseases which are covered so that you
don't have a problem understanding
whether this would fall under heart
probably would fall by heart slash lungs
or something else you know you know you
don't know because lot of us don't
understand the you know uh medical
terminology and all we are not prepared
we have not faced exigencies in our
lives so the idea is to make the selling
process more and more inclusive so you
say lot of it is covered except for this
one thing so people understand you know
what is known as a kind of allrisk
thought process that every risk is
covered except for this so you motor
vehicle accident everything is covered
as long as it's an accident not
something let's say your you know your
brake pad wearing away that's one thing
we very clearly says that anything where
it is wear and tier other than wear and
tier you know or you know something like
absolutely gross or willful negligence
we are covering all accidents you know
obviously if you go and you know drive
your vehicle down a hill we not going to
cover that because that's willful other
than that anything is you know whe it's
flood accident or whatever is covered
the third thing and which is important
same thing happens in travel as long as
you out of India we are trying to
broaden the coverage that you to include
the whole gamut of issues including
repatriation but let's say somebody's
covid and needs a long treatment we
repatriate him or her to to India so
that the treatment continues over the
next 30 days you know those kind of
issues which we are broadening more and
more so that everything exigency is
covered that is one approach so that you
understand what you get when you buy the
products is what you get because in your
mind should very clear that I I'm
covering myself comprehensively right B
and and this is very very important is
the whole EX ENT of how should I claim
and you know am I getting a fair amount
this is what I paid for if I'm do
getting paid so one is to pay you know
make sure that you reject very little
except for frauds you keep you know want
to keep paying everything which is you
know put as a claim as as long you as
there is coverage cover ideas to cover
increase the coverage you know
broad-base the coverage B when it comes
to the claims process we want to make it
easy to that's why digitalization comes
in a lot just send an SMS LOD in a claim
I'll reach out we'll try to to help you
on your documentation and very you know
very other important elements in case
you need to reur something more and more
we will now want to provide cash lless
cashless means that as long as you
intimate you know you you know you're
just in the insurance process you don't
to worry about how much you'll get back
entire thing is taken care of by us last
but not the least it's the whole issue
of if there are you know certain
deductions of various you know important
reasons like you know like for example
for in a hospital the you don't get
things which you incur on your own for
which is not not connected to treatment
let's say you know calls from the
hospital to your home they are not part
of your treatment or somebody you know
staying you know as a relative in your
thing and that's an extra thing which
you want to do other than that you know
we would want to cover everything under
the hospital you know policy similar
with motor C we want to you know take
care of everything more and more
nowadays you know what has become very
important is that deductions used to
happen because of your parts were
depreciated in motor now we are saying
that you know we have a coverage which
is called a zero depreciation coverage
which basically means that if your old
part you know old door gets you know
replaced I pay you 100% for that old
door not you know replace you know
cutting 50% because it's 10 years old
door right so you know that's where
depreciation is you know slowly we are
cutting down the amount we we pay back
you of course it means you need to pay
more at the time of uh taking the
premium but at least it cuts out the
resonance on claims similarly let's take
home insurance and all that more and
more we are saying that we'll give you
everything basis you know your cost of
reinstatement of that home M and you
know and we building up you know
coverages in such a manner it is
extremely easy to care caim send you
know images to us and we should be able
to look at that image and you know tell
you the amount which needs to be paid
and you go out and pay for repair of
your wall if a fire were to hit your
home you know home in that sense or you
know sometimes a breakdown could happen
so that's one one is Cash list to make
you know make sure there is payment
certainty and whever it's not cashless
to be able to pay most of it and be very
clear that this is the reason why it is
not covered because this was not
accidental and not meant to come under
Insurance okay so that's a broad way you
know we are you know trying apart from
increasing the coverage which is very
very important the other thing right
since I have you here Sanjay it's not
very often that we get to speak to
someone with the length and breadth of
experience that you have no I'm happy to
be part of this broadcast because
ultimately you know the idea of building
trust is through the media and you know
the communication thing people must
understand that you know insurance is
not only about you know people get
worried about fine lines and you know
things like people you know things more
and more our attempt has been to
broad-base coverage cover every kind of
risk which you can en under a particular
line of business in terms of risk and be
able to be very transparent in the way
we s the claims ideally cash when
everything gets paid or you know
reimburse you we should be able to pay
most of it unless there's something
which is not accidental yeah that's the
whole thought proc and people like you
help to broadcast that thought a lot
because India is still in the nent
underpenetrated
you know you know kind of having a lot
of trust issues around buying insurance
so we want to catch people young get
them to use Insurance products fast at
least starting with youngsters with
travel or something like that a small
you know you know medical policies and
all of that and then move them on to
bigger policies where they you know
carries them through life you know in
terms of risk and all of that idea is to
keep building Trust and communication is
the most important key there yeah yeah
you know I was coming to that I I want
to check with you since you have
visibility over a long period of time
you've seen The General insurance
industry evolve um you know if you could
look into the future sanay and give us a
sort of a idea of uh what that future is
going to look like for General insurance
and also with respect to claims
particularly are there any trends that
are shaping the future of the business
so one important uh thing is of course
risk risk will keep keep changing I told
you you know earlier you know in the
year 2000 you know emerging R like cyber
or something else was not very important
or even pandemic was not at the you know
you know you know at the Forefront in
terms of our risk thinking so as risk
changes people will buy covers which you
know changes their risk profile correct
and risk profile includes let's say now
everyone is transacting on the net or
the using a lot of uh data and all of
that they're exposed to R and hence they
need to be aware of getting insurance at
least for covers which helps them to
navigate such Financial exposure in case
something happens to them right now
that's one part but you know that's
going to develop strongly and it's going
to align with the way our lifestyles
change and how we move as a society
right but the more important thing and
it's very very important is how will the
products be configured and B how will
the products be delivered in the future
corre the idea you know the product
configur is going to become more and
more personalized which me you you know
tomorrow at this at the moment you're
treated as a class of consumer in that
sense let's say I give you you know
mandatory motor insurance I just treat
you as a new buyer of motor insurance
there's no difference the way we treat
you for third party Insurance between
let's say a person who buys Road you
know has to take Road tax pay
Road Road tax you know treat you
essentially that tomorrow all that will
change we will look at your records your
risk behavior your risk profile your
scores could be things like you know Cil
other credit scores various other things
we try to you know build that in already
you know I already articulated some
parts of that in pay as you drive and
pay how you drive where you become as a
very important element of how insurance
is designed and procured and you know so
it could be a cohort of people like you
or it could be just you you know for
example depending on you know how you
display you risk behavior how you drive
how you think how you take care of your
health whether you go for yearly
checkups or not you know could be a
factor in the way we design production
you know let's say if someone is a
diabetic whether he's controlling the
diabetic or not is hypertensive you
there'll be lot of chronic illnesses you
know as we the you know as we have a
long life so all these factors will
become very important in the way we
design the product as well as select the
consumer who comes in of course one of
the key things there will be one of the
key things there will be that we will
whole idea is to not only select the
right customers give them the right
products also give them the right price
for you know buying a product also in
the same time you know make sure that we
don't select the you know the bad
consumers the fraudulent one so that we
are able to then give you a right price
if I load my premium with people who
claim unnecessarily or who claim
fraudulently your premium which i p as a
good customer you'll be paying will be
that much more DED it's our duty to make
sure that difference will happen more
and more insurance will be able to
differentiate between good and bad
customers mod keep out the extremely bad
ones like the ones who are fraudulent
out of the portfolio and hence we'll be
able to give you a better Prem last but
not the least and which is very very
important the the amount of technology
which is now being used is at you know
we call it inure Tech at that moment is
at a fairly you know basic level so when
we move into the level of Technology
with some of the other Industries
including people who you know the
industries which launch rockets and all
of that use will slowly you know start
percolating not only in banking but also
in insurance so a lot of
the uh you know processes we have
whether it's claims process or product
design things will get automated simple
products and all will be able to to
automatically be able to you know uh
give you responses there'll be a lot of
voice which will speak to you for your
doubts and clarifications there'll be
lot of Tomorrow they'll be going forward
there will be a lot of artificial
intelligence which is going to be used
in paying your claim straightforward
without any intervention of people
correct you you know we see your vehicle
damage automatically I pay out that
claim without even interacting with you
and last but not the least there are
other Cutting Edge technology which is
coming in will will get Incorporated in
the insurance system because Insurance
system deals with the ecosystem and as
the ecosystem uses technology more where
whether it's hospitals doctors you know
let's say pandemic made them use them
much more garages all of that as the
ecosystem uses more technology let's say
5G coming in you know will will actually
you know again you know give a Leap
Forward for technology we will as insur
us start using the much more you know
thing customers will demand you know
that we shape up to the new technologies
coming so that's that's what I was doing
in terms of K gazing but the sky is a
limit uh the under penetration in India
is humongous we are at one % of the GDP
GDP you know in all mature countries it
is minimum of four to 5% I believe you
know with the new regulator you know
driving penetration you know in terms of
the new
German it is going to be a big big you
know push for you know getting more and
more people covered at least for the
basic risk health insurance the motor
gets covered that their motor cars get
covered at least for things like the
third party and finally you know every
time you travel on out of India you
should be covered by basic travel
insurance both domestically as well as
outside India so that you don't face
exigencies when you were abroad a lot of
people because they don't are not aware
of the risk they don't you know really
buy insurance just because they're not
aware I think awareness will take off
that is one big and a lot of uh social
media you know alternate media you know
people like you will really drive this
initiative of awareness because I think
some of the whole issue uh issues which
come across is not only awareness of the
need to buy insurance but also the kind
of products which are available and the
way the you know the you know entire
process is now getting digit digitalized
and simplified everything is available
cashless you can you know laun your laog
your things digitally lot of people
don't know about this so and because
that's what the reason one is a they are
not aware B their trust is both of these
things I require I think requires a lot
of absolutely yeah you know sanj I have
to tell you don't put that crystal ball
away just as yet because I still have I
think we'll still have need for it as we
go on in the conversation but a few
things have come out very clearly hyper
personalization in a sense if I were to
use that word the use of technology in
the way you know products are going to
be not just you know crafted but also
delivered to uh Forks you know awareness
levels certainly are going to be on the
high people are I think um learning how
to unpack otherwise a complicated word
like insurance I mean up until now um
I'm hoping podcast like this help them
understand the fine print speaking of
print and stuff like that here's here's
a sort of a technical issue question um
what was the intent behind the use and
file regulation Sanjay while it will
make the product launch faster is it not
going to dilute the quality of the
product no so the uh essential
difference between you using file and
file in use you know when it started
there was you know and when there was
some regulatory changes you know
sometime back you know a few years back
whole idea was to make sure that usern
file happen more in the corporate space
products for corporates because they
understand how they buy insurance and
why they buy insurance and you know the
the chances of Miss selling are very
little in that you know segment then
then you know filing use was put in
place for you know B Toc kind of
products business direct to Consumers
which is Health motor travel on these
things which are between to individual
customers now what happened there was
the Regulator wanted to make make sure
there have two things one is the
coverage is exactly as for what was
promised the processes were the wordings
the you know the everything was as per
promise and B you know make sure that
whatever was put in terms of uh our
filings as the prices for such products
and all are kind of adhered to so that
we do not have any dissonance when it
comes to charging the same rate let's
say you have a twin sister I can't
charge you you and both stay the same
house I can't be both of you let's say
buying something very similar let's say
personal accident and I just can't
charge you know one 100 rupees for you
and you know your twin sister 500 rupes
just like that because I get this
opportunity to charge at 500 you know so
you know we had to do it as per risk so
both of you are the same age I would
same profile I would go for you're
living in the same place and had this
like kind of say the same profession I
would have to charge you similarly right
right now that is something which The
Regulators finally kind of got
confidence in insurance companies having
you know putting the underlying
regulations which have now now come in
uh and has been here to stay in terms of
policyholder protection how do you file
what do you look at in terms of pricing
they say that now given the need for
product Innovation not only for having
much more products in the market for
various niches but also even for this
hyper personalization we add a lot of
factors I'll put in a lot of add-ons you
know which are important to you let's
say you know me for example I could have
an add-on which takes care of my
spectacles now it's normally not covered
but there could be people who would want
to coverage for their you know breakage
of spectacles as part of the health
insurance policy now for that cohort I
didn't need don't need to go back to the
regulator and get it approved and me all
of that you can put it in put in the you
know the technical note you know upload
it in the regulatory site and have you
make sure that it is as per regulations
the way we are you know construct it and
go ahead and launch the product and see
how it you know progresses the idea is
to Foster innovation time to you know
speed to you know launch is there and
finally lot of iterations take place you
know a lot of these Innovations which
are H will lead a lot of now let's say
this spectacle thing maybe is very
important for me that you know I go out
of the market and look at my 100 of my
health insurance customer none of them
are interested in this particular
obviously that not become a thing I have
to withraw that particular product you
know that withdrawal process also
becomes very seamless now for me right
they have certain rules on how to
withdraw and all of that so that's why
using file comes in it is part of the
whole Innovation drive it is part of the
whole idea to bring in
responsibility of how to you know U Get
retail customers into your uh into the
insurance fold develop trust and be able
to do that so the first thing forward is
the regulator started trusting us to be
able to do all of this and we believe
that as a market we are mature enough to
handle these things ourselves yeah no
now again to come to the lay uh you know
View I'm quite certain they are waiting
for me to ask you this question uh
Sanjay why have and here's where I want
you to look a little into the you know
immediate past why have insurance
premiums uh risen so sharply in the past
year or so what is and what's the trend
going to look like going forward as well
uh insurance premiums have gone up
strongly because of two reasons let's
take two different categories health
insurance it has grown up for various
reasons that Healthcare inflation you
know come is part of the healthcare
ecosystem you know there is always
inflation sometimes it is much higher
than the Consumer inflation which we
experience as consumers cor healthare is
a very very people intensive kind of
Technology intensive kind of area where
actually costs increase because the
quality of healthcare needs to improve
the kind of procedures we want as a as
people are also we don't want basic uh
stuff we want people to really do huge
amount of tests and all of that so all
of that adds to you know the healthcare
as they call it the healthare seeking
Behavior has also changed healthare
access Behavior has also changed amongst
consumers they want to access more
healthare and because if you access more
sophisticated healthare it will cost a
lot but bear in mind that some of this
is good thing for the country what we
are seeing is healthare cost improving
is something which makes Healthcare
available at a certain quality healthare
available at here for radical treatments
for critical illnesses which were not
available in country let's a few decades
are or we don't have to travel to us for
everything right or Europe for
everything so now they are now available
loc because of the Technologies coming
and all they available loc and of course
they'll cost a lot of money but they'll
be at one tenth of the price of a
US you know that's the you know
difference always a difference between
us and you will get the same care with
you know the best of doctors and best of
uh you know let's a technology uh you
know be it scanning technology or
operating technology you know like you
know laser knives you know what have you
so many kinds of new technologies coming
in which you could do do it in they cost
a lot of money and hence they charge a
lot of money and you need to pay for
that that that is what health insurance
that's why we have started encouraging
our people to take higher coverage
higher the coverage you know you you get
better bank for your B for the insurance
when a critical illness happens that's
where insurance is supposed to be right
the second pattern which is very
important is the whole issue of let's
take motor and other things in fact
motor it's a drive the other way around
now motor we are going the drive in
terms of hyper personalization so if you
are a good driver Drive
less I mean you actually your premiums
will go down cor and which is as at part
let's say you know you travel to Pune
every day you going to consume more
petrol so same thing with you know
Insurance also your insurance you know
should be you know you know higher if
you travel to Pune every day from Mumbai
for your but if you travel from let's
say on Sundays or Saturdays you you know
use your second vehicle it should
drastically bring down your so this
hyper personalization is going to help
third party premium is actually as of
now even now in India is regulator
defined so we have no role in that it
all depends on the number of accidents
uh which happen on the road as the
government takes more initiative on the
number of accidents it should bring you
know rain it down and B also because
it's unlimited liability the courts also
decide um liability and they keep paying
more and more based on various aspects
of your income and people who's been hit
so that has started going up because
minimum daily wages in India started
going up over the years so the court
judgments are more hence third party
premium sometimes and travel travel is
now again hyper uh kind of we are
getting it into areas of that so you
would if you travel to uh areas where
medical cost is very high you'll get a
high premium if you travel to areas
where medical cost is very low you're
going to get very low premium
that's you know premiums but what about
you you brought up Healthcare inflation
and I am a bit greedy usually on I Cafe
and I try to decode everything that
comes at me in the course of the
conversation so got to ask you this why
is Healthcare inflation high in India
help us understand that Sanjay so two
three reasons uh one of course is the
fact that a lot of new technologies is
coming into India so Indian healthc care
the amount of spends which you are doing
so Indian the amount of spend let's say
even the government does does as
Healthcare spend it's one of the lowest
in the world you know correct that is
now significantly increasing not only in
the public space there's also a lot of
stuff happening on the private space we
cap you know even capitalist now flowing
into healthare they have realized the
inadequacy during the pandemic it really
brought us lot of stuff in terms of
faults fault lines in healthare
treatment so lot of funding is going to
happen as we go forward see I think a
lot of the you know increase in
healthcare uh treatment is the fact that
we never adopted technology to a large
meure as we adopt technology and scale
correct let's say tele medicine for
example you can have access to
healthcare sitting at remote locations
also correct look at the amount of cost
we people go through uh because they're
not able to get good quality Health Care
at the place where they
reside and if they all keep coming to
the Metros or few you know very good
tertiary hospitals cost are going to
shoot up because there is limited you
know capacity as healthare decentralizes
good quality hospitals slash centers
where which can develop under PPP
initiatives to be able to deliver at
least preventive care up to a certain
level the basic Pro procedures are able
to be you know handled there for example
covid taught us a lot now you you we
heard of situation where the covid you
know the covid serious cases where it
required ICU treatment had to be brought
to Metro Cities A lot of people came
back from the things now people have
realized that people are setting up
capacities lot of uh government extra
government authorities are working
towards so that we have enough oxygen
enough stuff to handle you know
infectious diseases which take a lot of
our healthare costs you know even at the
local know situations he does two things
it you know brings down Healthcare
inflation it it brings a lot of patient
inconvenience because he doesn't have to
travel he doesn't worry about his family
traveling to Metro to look after him for
a critical illness and last but not the
least it it has a huge impact on health
insurance premium for the long term the
lesser the inflation the the more
affordable you know Insurance becomes so
there are two parts which in insurance
premum is subject to one is inflation
the other one is fraud so we try to you
know take care of both is something we
can do Healthcare inflation is out of
our hands because it depends on the
healthare sector so we keep hoping that
as it scales as it's used more
technology as more and more procedures
are handled at the placed where they
ought to be MH I think we could see a
significant reduction in cost as we go
forward in terms of the number of
procedures you know per procedure cost
for this country right while I told you
don't put away the crystal ball for just
a bit you know Sanjay I realize that
you're not going to be putting it away
at all because you have one eye on the
future as you craft all of these success
stories for IC lombar and by extension
the uh the health industry insurance
industry as well and thank you so much
for joining us today and helping us you
know navigate this very difficult to
understand space of claim settlement
that and how you know all the various
things that inform the choices are the
direction that this area is taking
consumer Behavior technology the
pandemic and then some uh it's been
great enlightening chatting with you
today actually it was wonderful talking
to you you know questions were very very
relevant it really Drew out a lot of
thoughts in me which you know has also
set me thinking I you know you know the
issues around you know trust how do I
keep generating how do I communicate
awareness and all of that one of the key
things which I think uh I'm always uh
you know uh kind of really really
conscious of is the need to make sure
that in the customer's mind once he's
bought insurance he needs to get peace
of mind you know it's like you know when
once you brought a TV you know in one of
your things you know you don't worry
about whether the TV is going to work or
not work or come to your home or not
home you know bought a TV you know your
only thought would will it last 20 years
or 10 years you just worry about that
correct so that's the only difference
when you buy you don't worry about
whether it'll get delivered at your home
whether it'll be switched on or not you
know that if it's not switched on
they'll replace it correct so so so
that's where fundamental trust is and
you know that's what I would you know
want insure you know insurers to
propagate and the persons who insure
from us assume that claims is for you to
take it it's an intachable product it's
not deliver the ram when you buy the
product but whenever it happens will be
there if it is not you know if you're
not getting paid it is something wrong
in the way we we designed products and
you chose the products and so that's
something I can assure you that we'll
keep working towards making sure that it
should be covered in your policy as long
as it's a good clip it should get get
played you know seamlessly without you
worrying about whe you know you know
whether you should get it or not and
just like consumer durable which you buy
it should work you know when you buy it
for the first time you should be
delighted in here in this case you buy
it I don't want you to experience but if
you do ever experience it as a consumer
it should you know bring peace of mind
absolutely and I must thank you then in
advance for the Peace of Mind Sanjay and
thank you also one more time for joining
us in I Cafe that that's our Moto yes
absolutely new
all you were listening to Il Cafe we
have you covered
[Music]